Now, I'm going to walk you through how to make the appropriate XML layout
现在我将逐步指导大家如何做出适当的 XML 布局更改
changes, so that our app matches the red lines from our designer.
使应用符合设计师用红色线条标示的要求
So, let's start with an easy change first.
先从简单的更改开始
I noticed right away that there's too much padding in the current
我很快发现当前版本的应用中存在太多的
version of our app.
内边距
So, when I scroll in the app,
当我滚动应用的时候
notice that the padding goes all the way around the whole list.
发现整个列表都存在内边距
Even if I scroll the list, the padding is still there.
即使我在滚动列表 也存在内边距
So that tells me that the padding is probably in the list view.
所以可以判断内边距可能存在于 ListView 中
Remember that we declare the list view XML element in the word list XML file.
我们在 Word_list.xml 文件中声明了 ListView xml 元素
And sure enough, inside I see that the padding values are set on it.
猜的没错 我看见这里设置了内边距值
So let's remove all these padding values.
我们删除所有这些内边距值
Also if we go to our dimensions.XML file,
此外 转到 dimensions.XML 文件
my code doesn't revert to these dimension values anymore.
会发现我的代码没有再转换为这些尺寸值
The ones for activity_horizontal main and activity_vertical main.
即 activity_horizontal 尺寸和 activity_vertical 尺寸值
So I can delete these two lines from the values/dimensions.xml file
所以我可以从 values/dimensions.xml 文件中删了这两行
where the activity_horizontal_margin and
在这里 activity_horizontal_margin 和
the activity_vertical_margin were initially set to 16 DPs.
activity_vertical_margin 一开始设为了 16dp
So I'm going to go ahead and leave this other dimension that's still in this
剩下的这个尺寸还留在文件里
file, this one here for list_item_height because we'll still need that one.
它针对的是 list_item_height 因为我们还需要这个值
You also notice that we have one more dimensions file that's left, so
你还会发现 我们还存在一个尺寸文件
this one for w820dp.
这个针对的是 w820dp
This file is used for larger screen devices.
这个文件用于大屏幕设备
And here inside we have an even larger value set for
在这个文件里 我们为 activity_horizontal_margin
the activity_horizontal_margin.
设置了一个更大的值
But we don't need this dimension any more, so we can actually go ahead and
但我们不再需要这个尺寸
delete this entire file.
可以直接删了整个文件
So I'm going to head over to Project, navigate to that file, and delete it.
转到“项目 (Project)” 然后转到该文件 删了该文件
Now let's see what the app looks like on our device.
现在看看应用在设备上的运行效果
So tapping to the Numbers activity, nice.
点按 NumbersActivity 不错
So those code changes got rid of the 16 DP border around the whole list.
更改这些代码后 去掉了整个列表四周的 16dp 边界
Nice job.
不错
Now let's move on to the list item layout.
现在转到 list_item 布局
And if you remember, each list item should have a minimum height of 88 dps.
如果还记得的话 每个列表项应该至少高 88dp
Now that number sounds familiar it's because we saved it off earlier
如果觉得该数字听起来熟悉的话 那是因为
in our dimensions.xml file.
我们之前将其保存在了 dimensions.xml 文件中
So we saved it under the list item height value.
我们将其保存在了 list_item_height 值中
So I want to copy that for use later.
复制下 稍后会用到
That means if we head back to the list item layout, we refer to it as such.
返回 list_item 布局 我们是这么引用它的
So here I'm setting the minimum height to refer to @dimen/list_item_height.
我将 minimumHeight 设为等于 @dimen/list_item_height
Now notice here I prefer to set the minimum height value to be 88 dps
注意 我在这里将最低高度值设为 88dp
instead of fixing the height to be 88 exactly.
而不是将高度值固定为 88dp
So this combination of values means that the linear layout must be 88 dps
这组值表示 LinearLayout 的高度
in height at least but
必须至少为 88dp
can be taller if needed depending on the content inside the list item.
但是可以更高 取决于列表项中的内容
Now in the design mock of our Numbers activity, notice that the background of
在 NumbersActivity 的设计模型中
each list item Is this ten color given by this hex value?
注意每个列表项的背景颜色是棕褐色 用这个十六进制值表示
So we actually already use that color in the main activity screen.
我们已经在 MainActivity 屏幕中用到该颜色
So we store that color in the colors.xml file.
我们将该颜色存储在了 colors.xml 文件中
And we have the hex value for that color that we need here.
并在这里设置了该颜色的十六进制值
So back on the list item layout, who referred to that color resource?
回到 list_item 布局 谁引用了该颜色资源？
So here in the root LinearLayout, I've set the background of the whole
在这里的根 LinearLayout 中 我将整个线性布局的背景颜色
linear layout to be this @color/tan_background color resource and
设为这个 @color/tan_background 颜色资源
we can refer to the color resource using this @color syntax/name
我们可以使用“@color/ 颜色资源的名称”
of the color resource that we want.
来引用所需的颜色资源
Now let's look back at our red lines.
再去看看红色标示
The image should be a square with both 88 digits for height and width.
图片应该是正方形的 宽高都应是 88dp
So essentially it should be as tall as a list item.
所以本质上 它应该和列表项一样高
So here in the dimensions XML file, we store that 88 dips
在这个 dimensions.xml 文件中
in the dimensions resource already so we can go ahead and refer to that.
我们已经在尺寸资源中存储该 88dp 值 所以可以直接引用该值
And this means if we ever decide that the list item should change in height.
如果我们想更改列表项的高度
So maybe increase to 96 dps.
例如增加到 96dp
Well we could just change it in one place and
我们可以直接在一个地方做出更改
all the places that reference this dimension will automatically be updated.
所有引用该尺寸的地方都会自动更新
So back to my list item layout inside the image view,
回到 list_item 布局 在 ImageView 中
I'm going to change the width and height to refer to the dimension resource
我将宽度和高度更改为引用该尺寸资源
called list_item_height.
称作 list_item_height
And lastly,
最后
we can remove this source attribute that uses the basket placeholder icon.
我们可以删除这个使用篮子占位符图标的资源属性
Now there we can correctly set the image dynamically when the app is running,
现在当应用运行时 我们可以动态地设置正确的图片
there's no need to have that attribute anymore.
没必要再使用这个属性了
Now let's see those coaching does we made work as expected.
现在看看更改这些代码后 应用是否能如预期的正常运行
So here's the app running our device and tapping into the Numbers activity, nice.
这是应用在设备上的运行效果 点按 NumbersActivity 不错
So the image is now a square with dimensions 88 dp by 88 dp.
图片现在变成方形 尺寸为 88dp x 88dp
And the background of the image is this nice tan color, so
图片的背景颜色是棕褐色
it's looking good so far.
到目前为止 一切看起来正常
Now let's move on to the text part.
再转到文字部分
So first, we have to set the background to be the same orange color for
首先 我们需要将背景颜色设为和文字部分相同的
the text area.
橘色
And this orange color is the same as the background color that we use for
这个橘色和我们在 MainActivity 中用于 Numbers 类别的
the numbers category in the main activity.
背景颜色相同
So remember its hex color,
它的十六进制颜色 FT 8E09
FT 8E09 should already be in our colors.xml file.
应该已经位于 colors.xml 文件中
And sure enough, it's defined as the color resource called category_numbers.
并且定义为颜色资源 称为 category_numbers
So back in our list item layout, let's add that.
回到 list_item 布局 我们添加这项内容
So for the LinearLayout that contains our two TextViews, we're going to set
对于这个包含两个 TextView 的 LinearLayout
its background color to the category underscore numbers resource and
我们将其背景颜色设为 category_numbers
refer to it as @color/category_numbers.
指代为 @color/category_numbers
So by setting the color on this linear layout,
通过在这个 LinearLayout 中设置该颜色
will only influence the background of these text views.
将只影响到这些 TextView 的背景颜色
Now let's go back to the red lines and see what's left to do.
现在再去看看红色标示 看看还剩下哪些需要改动
So we need to change the font stylings of these text views,
我们需要更改这些 TextView 的字体样式
they should be of a white font color and the miwok word should be bold.
应该是白色 米沃克单词应该是粗体
And both should be a font size 18 SP
并且二者的字体大小都应该是 18sp
which if you remember from the last course, maps the text appearance medium.
如果还记得上一门课程的内容的话 对应的是 textAppearanceMedium
On the miwok text view also the text appearance attribute
在 Miwok TextView 中 我将 textAppearance 属性设为
to be text appearance medium.
textAppearanceMedium
And so this gets us the font size of 18 SP.
这会使字体大小变成 18sp
Then I'll set the text color to be white and
然后将文本颜色设为白色
I know that the Android framework has a predefined color resource.
我知道 Android 框架具有一个预定义的颜色资源
So I can use that one by simply calling @android:color/white.
我可以通过直接调用 @android:color/white 使用该资源
And lastly I want to set the text style to be bold.
最后 我将文本样式设为粗体
So on or be something similar for
我希望默认文字
the text you show in the default or English translations.
即英语翻译保持相似的样式
So I want the text appearance to be medium and the color to be white but
textAppearance 设为 Medium 颜色设为白色
I don't want to be bald.
但不希望设为粗体
So I won't copy that line.
所以不复制这行代码
All right let's check it on a device now so tap into the Numbers activity.
在设备上看看效果 点按 NumbersActivity
So the appearance of the text views and the background looks correct but
TextView 的外观和背景颜色看起来正确
the position of our two text views doesn't look quite right.
但是两个 TextView 的位置看起来不太正确
So right now, they are squished up into the top left corner
现在 它们被挤在了橘色背景所示的
of the vertical linear layout that shown here in the orange background.
垂直线性布局的左上角
So if we take a look back our red lines, we see that what we need
再回去看看红色指示 发现我们需要
is to have our two text views vertically centered within the list item.
使这两个 TextView 在列表项中保持垂直居中
So to figure that out, let's first figure out the bounds of each text view
要实现这一样式 我们先看看每个 TextView 的边界
and to help us out, I'm going to draw on the show layout bounds
为此 我将在“设置”菜单中的开发者选项里
under the developer's options in the settings menu.
打开“显示布局边界”
So remember how to get there?
还记得怎么找到该选项吗？
Go back to settings, scroll down to developer options and
转到“设置”向下滚动到开发者选项
then a little bit more than halfway down should be show layout bounds.
然后往下多滚动几次 找到“显示布局边界”
So let's go back to Army walk up.
返回我们的 Miwok 应用
Now with the layout bounds showing, I can see that our two text views
显示布局边界后 可以看出我们的两个 TextView
are squished up into the top edge of the vertical linear layout.
被挤到了垂直线性布局的顶部边缘
Now I need to move them down a little bit more, so
我需要将它们往下移移
they take up more vertical height in the linear layout.
使它们在线性布局中占用更多的高度
Now there are a number of ways to tweak this layout to make it work and
我们可以通过多种方式来更改该布局
here's one way.
下面介绍一种方式
So from the last course,
在上一门课程中
we learned that we can assign layout weights to the children views.
我们学习了我们可以向子视图分配布局权重
So they take up more available space in the parent linear layout.
使它们占用父线性布局的更多可用空间
Now I can assign the height of each view to be 0 and give each of them a weight
现在我可以将每个视图的高度设为 0 然后 weight 设为 1
of one, so that the vertical space is divided evenly between both child views.
这样垂直空间就在这两个子视图之间均匀分布
In addition, I can use an attribute called gravity.
此外 我还可以使用 gravity 属性
So for the first text view, I'll set its gravity value to be bottom
对于第一个 TextView 我将其 gravity 设为 bottom
push you position the text content to be at the bottom of the view.
使文字内容转到该视图的底部
And for the second text view, I'll set its gravity tribute to be top.
对于第二个 TextView 我将其 gravity 属性设为 top
And now position the text view to be at the top of the text view.
使文字内容位于该 TextView 的顶部
And back in the code, this is what it should look like.
回到代码部分 代码应该是这样的
So the miwok_text_view has a width of match_parent which will fill
Miwok 的 TextView 宽度为 match_parent
the rest of the list item layout.
并且 list_item 布局的其他部分也是这样的
Its height will be zero dps and its weight will be one,
高度将为 0dp weight 为 1
the default view also has a with a match parent.
默认视图的宽度也是 match_parent
Its height is also zero dps and its weight is also one.
高度也是 0dp weight 也是 1
So this means that the two text views will split the available height
意味着这两个视图将平分父线性布局的
in the parent linear layout.
可用高度
Then we set the gravity which changes where the content inside the viewer's
然后设置 gravity 该属性会改变内容在
position.
视图中的位置
But note that it doesn't change the size of the view.
但是注意 它不会改变视图的尺寸
Here we've positioned the text inside the Miwok text view to be at the bottom
这里 我们将 Miwok TextView 中的文字放在底部
and the text inside the default text view to be at the top.
将默认 TextView 中的文字放在顶部
And this is what it looks like on the device.
看看在设备上的运行效果
So tapping into Numbers,
点按 Numbers
we see that the two text views are centered within the list item.
我们看到两个 TextView 都在列表项中居中了
So let's see what it looks like for the other activities.
看看其他 Activity 的效果
So these are looking good so
看起来不错
the only thing now that we need to fix is the background list item color.
现在唯一需要修复的就是列表项背景颜色
So they're not all using this orange and instead are using the proper color for
使它们不再都使用橘色 而是各自具有对应的
each category.
类别颜色